supply and demand order blocks liquidity
inducement institutional candles
imbalances and overall smart money
Concepts in the recent few years it's
all we see everywhere every Trader now
is an SMC Trader and that's absolutely
great great job to all creators and
Traders actually going out there testing
that stuff showing us how it's done
giving us tutorials I've personally
learned a lot and I've watched them all
however in the end of the day every
single strategy works and the strategies
that work best are the simple ones
because remember Simplicity is key in
trading if you do not understand what
you do what your strategy is and you
make it too hard and you go out there
and you absorb all of that information
and you think that if you combine all of
that information you're actually going
to get the Holy Grail what you're gonna
keep failing right you as a Trader have
to sit down and put together a strategy
that you understand and it works for you
because remember every Trader is unique
you have to find and craft your own
niche in the markets take some bits from
me take some bits from someone else take
some bits from somebody else go on your
charts test it out and then see what
happens
in this video I'm gonna break down how I
personally use the plan demand in my
training and I'm Gonna Keep it extremely
simple while still walking you through
the theory the foundations and also
trying to give you as many examples as
possible combining this with Market
structure has been incredible for me as
it offers a high Precision areas of
value where you have increased odds of
price moving away from those zones right
so I hope you are actually excited about
this so get your notebooks ready cut out
all distractions put down your phone put
down your charts and please watch the
video Until the End and even watch it a
few times watch it once first for just
to walk through it then twice to take
notes and then three times to actually
take notes on your notes right until you
digest everything and make sure you also
keep revisiting the market structure
video because a gap in understanding of
your Market structure will result in
your supply and demand zones not working
properly alright so make sure you do
that well without further Ado we have a
lot to cover so let's get into it
foreign
with an introduction to supply and
demand to gain a fundamental
understanding of what it actually is so
what is supply and demand well pretty
much supply and demand is what drives
all markets not only the Forex Market
not only the stock market every market
like eggs bread oil whatever when demand
is greater than Supply which means that
people buy that stuff people want that
stuff prices are automatically going to
rise and when Supply is greater than
demand which means that people are
either selling or they refrain from
buying because price is too expensive
then price will automatically fall right
and this happens in every Market take
for example an ice cream of Ben and
Jerry's here it usually costs like six
euros nobody buys this in six euros so
what usually the supermarket does is
they run sales right because they have a
lot of supply of Ben and Jerry's but
there is no demand at this price so what
they do is they decrease the price in
order to increase demand so then people
go in a lot of Demands they buy all the
ice cream but then they don't just want
to keep throwing away that ice cream at
this high demand so again prices rise
and then this cycle keeps repeating
right that was a little bit of a funny
example but hopefully you get the point
on a price chart supply and demand is
usually interpreted as oversold so you
either have supplied running out and
demand coming in or over but demand
running out and Supply coming in and our
task as Traders is to identify at what
zones price will be oversold so we can
buy it or overbought in order to sell it
again going back to the previous lesson
this is simply buying low and selling
high and how we do this when we utilize
supply and demand zones once again
combined with Market structure and there
are a lot of theories so we have the
Wyckoff price cycle right the market
accumulating while it's being oversold
so right now demand this is starting to
get in it pushes up then we have
distribution the market is overbought
and then Supply is greater than demand
so Market starts going down and what
you're usually going to see is as I told
you
the market moves in Cycles they're going
to have up you're gonna have down you're
gonna have up you're gonna have down
right and this is again Market structure
but also within the foundation of Market
structure supply and demand is also
right there right and then of course you
have uh this here this is more like
again I think it's also whack-off
schematic this more uh takes into
account also Market structure so what we
have right here is again the market
accumulating it's starting pushing up
pushing up pushing up getting into that
overbought state it starts to distribute
then it starts pushing down pushing down
pushing down and pretty much this is
Market structure so there are numerous
ways to study supply and demand but I
really want you to understand like
really the foundation of it so
how and why do supply and demand zones
form so we're gonna get a little bit
more technical right there and I wanna
always walk you through the psychology
behind because if you don't ask the very
important question why why do supply and
demand zones form and how do they
actually form then you're missing out so
what is the psychology behind
I call those guys the bfis uh those are
big financial institutions Banks hedge
funds Pension funds those are the guys
with the money and they do not trade
with one lot like us even a hundred Lots
right because this is all retail they
trade in thousands of millions of lots
and they probably don't even utilize lot
sizes right they're probably trading
just cash I don't know nobody knows so
whoever pretends to know how the bfis or
how the institutions are trading
you probably don't right
very important to understand also is
that trading is a zero-sum game so you
have a positive sum game and you have a
zero-sum game a zero-sum game is that
when somebody wins someone else has to
lose in order for someone then to sales
one lot of your USD someone else has to
buy one lot of your USD and some of
those people right one of those people
are is gonna lose
while a positive sum game is for example
a service so if I give you my mentorship
you pay me money which is my reward and
then I give you the mentorship which is
your reward so it's a win-win situation
right there is growth it's a positive
sum game but a zero-sum game one is
gonna one person is gonna win the other
person is gonna lose so in order for
someone to sell one lot someone who has
to buy one lot in order to meet the
other side
and usually we do not need to worry
about the execution of our trades and
about liquidity because yeah we can
always go to our broker and put as many
Lots as we want but those bfis they do
worry about it so let me give you an
example imagine that bank X I don't know
Barclays JPMorgan they want to place one
million lot long on your USD
respectively what are they gonna need is
one million Lots shorts at the same time
so their order can get executed because
if they want to buy one that they need
to buy it from somebody right so if they
want to buy one million Lots somebody
else has to sell them one million lots
and usually uh that seller at one
million Lots it's not just gonna be one
person it is us it is the whole market
so they need to actually find and
generate those 1 million lots of shorts
how do they do this well they trick
Traders into selling and buying the
market and they generate the patterns we
all know double tops triple tops Flex
trend lines Head and Shoulders triangles
pendants all of this stuff and they make
it look really good so that a lot of
people start buying and selling and they
build liquidity in the market however
what's the bad thing is that after those
formations are ready and people are in
then banks will usually launch a big
fake position and what this fake
position does it it stops out all the
Traders it is very important to
understand that when you get a stop loss
your order automatically turns into the
opposite order so a stop loss on a buy
position so if you take a long trade
right now and you get a stop loss then
immediately after hitting stop loss you
turn into a cell you pretty much sell
sold what you bought right so if enough
people who are long for example and all
of those are people are stopped out they
pretty much offer those sales to the to
the bank who wants to buy right and this
is how Banks get their liquidity
however what is also important to note
is that when they launched this fake
move to stop out the Traders they also
run into some drawdown because in order
for them to like launch this fake move
they still have to enter the market and
this is usually why they will come back
to that same place they launch their
fake orders uh mitigate those losses at
break even and then launch again with
their own liquidity so this is really
theoretical I want to jump into an
example right now and actually walk you
through how that happens but hopefully
so far you're getting the point say at
this precise moment a bank wants to buy
one million loss exactly what was said
before what do they need in order to buy
those one minute Lots they need 1
million cells right then you they need
one million lots to be on the sales side
in order for them to put their one
minute Lots on the buy side so what they
start doing is they start generating the
patterns right they make a double tap
what is right there a lot of sellers are
entering right so what do they need they
need sellers
here we have a double bottom what does
this make Traders do it makes them go
long right so very good they go long
right now what is below the double
bottom is their stop losses and if a buy
gets a stop loss what does it turn into
a sell order so what they're going to be
doing is they're going to be
accumulating price doing some math stuff
and then all of a sudden you get this
very huge momentous move below or above
respectively in an opposite example that
pattern right and this is what I call
the fake move and I in in this lesson
we're going to be seeing the fake move
drawn with this red kind of rectangle
right and if all the stop losses right
now of the buyers are taking in they
turn into sell orders and also what
happens is that there are people that
are looking to take the breakout so for
a lot of people this is a structure
break they have their sales stop below
right so people are entering shorts as
the market breaks what do the bank need
they need shorts right then the market
gives you a little bit of a pullback a
lot of people start entering shorts from
here why because it's a lower high what
do the banks need they still need shorts
they're still putting in their one
minute Lots right and then what suddenly
happens is the market expands massively
so after the bank actually got their 1
billion sales they launched their buys
and they might not launch all of the
buys at the same time so maybe they just
launched like uh uh 500k Lots right
there right but what I want you to pay
attention to right now is what I told
you about this um if I just delete all
of this this fake position right here so
in order for them to make this fake
position they need to sell right so when
they sold right there and then when they
bought right here they're running into
drawdown because they're running in
sales right there so what happens right
now is price reaches to a satisfactory
level right and then they take some take
profits they take some partials then
they start the process again right they
start generating the pairs double tap
right there all right the market starts
pulling back what do we have right there
double top who do we have right there
sellers oh double bottom the market is
making a higher low who do we have right
there buyers right the market comes in
stop loss of the sellers takes in new
buyers the market goes down stop loss of
the buyers takes in new Sellers and
stops out uh everybody right then the
market comes in just before this move
which is usually going to be called an
order block or supply and demand Zone
which we're going to be covering a
little bit later and then they start
accumulating again boom boom boom boom
boom boom and then again they launched a
new fake move into the previous fake
move but with the new fake move they're
gonna close the previous one at break
even and again if they launched sales
right there
what do they get right now buys and this
is exactly what they're going to be
doing they're just shifting their orders
to buys and then usually see the market
massively plug it into the highs so in
this case they also use their own
liquidity
from here and of course they still
generated some right there
so hopefully this little Theory makes uh
sense again it's a little bit complex
and again I don't want to get way too
detailed about it but I just want you to
understand how it works right so this is
the basic supply and demand Zone Theory
this is when you have usually an
accumulation manipulation below that
um initiations outside then you come
back re-test the zone and then the
market usually goes in the in the
overall direction this is one type of
supply and demand zone I'm using and
there is the second type this is pretty
much the the rally base rally drop base
drop right so what happens is the market
this is usually happens after this so
after this develops this is how we see
usually supply and demand form as the
market is in a nice uptrend or a
downtrend so I have this very nice push
the market pulls back and start
generating like a little bit of a
pennant a little bit of a triangle right
so people start selling right there
people are looking at this triple bottom
they start buying what does the market
do they launch a fake move
right so what happens is stop loss of
buyers new sellers enter the market as
well on the move up they take out the
stop loss of the sellers they take out
all the buyers then they return back to
their fake move right and then they
launch again exactly the same situation
right there on the on the sales side all
right so study those two examples this
is the theory
here isn't a real example okay so what
do we have right there is something
similar right so say at this precise
moment right there Banks wanted to buy
that one million Lots right so what they
do again the market looks like it's
bearish but there is probably something
on the left right we don't know we're
just focusing on pure price right there
so what the market does is again it does
this right boom boom boom boom boom
likes a little bit of a choppiness then
it sharply moves to the downside break
structure down if there are people that
are buying right there they're all stop
loss and there are people also selling
right there with a stop loss above here
then the market goes and creates a trend
change so what is this guys this is
Market structure
train change and then again so this is
their fake orders right there then the
market pushes up and then starts to
consol it right and usually the Asian
range which we're going to be covering a
little bit later is a really good
example of building liquidity so the
market pulls back pulls back pulls back
and solids for a little bit tricks
buyers buyers to enter right there are
trick seller center right there and what
they do is they launch to get another
fake move to the downside where exactly
to the previous one so they close their
positions that are on the cell right
they're turning into buys and look at
the expansion there is expansion and
then again so this is the first example
that I showed you so this is the first
supply and demand Zone and there are the
second one so then you have a base
Harlow har High pulls back into the base
goes on and makes a new heart High there
is a new base push pull back right pulls
back into the base makes a new high then
here for a brief moment the market
needed lots of liquidity so then they
gave this big stock hunt to the downside
and again this happens right so how do
you know that this is a stop hunt
because according to me here we have a
shift of Market structure but then the
market immediately came in and shifted
to the upside so then I can say okay
well yeah this was the liquidity grab
right now we're bullish again and I will
be looking to to flow with the market
bullish as long as it goes
so that is the that's the first example
hopefully it's clear there is another
one right this one is also a very nice
textbook one so again guys pause on
those charts study them carefully I'm
gonna be giving you away the PDF as well
so you can watch this at your own at
your own time
again bank right there decides to buy
something what they start doing is they
start making a range and usually once
again as I told you the Asian range is a
really good confidence for that they
consolidate consolidate consolidate then
what they do is they launch this fake
move so what is happening right here a
lot of people that are buying this
support they get stop loss A lot of
people on this breakout are entering
also into sales okay so there are a lot
of Voters being transacted just after we
broke this level right there the market
pushes down we get a little bit of an
accumulation then you can see Boom the
market expands what happens is we have a
trend change so the market aligns
bullish okay then we pull back into the
zone
we pull back into the zone and you can
definitely be looking to take a trade
right there absolutely right then the
market massively initiates outside once
again and then again as I keep saying
the market is not perfect so we still
have this fake move and again we don't
know so a big question you might have
right now is okay how do we know when
you have a range like this where exactly
is it going to retest is it going to
retest the top is it going to retest the
middle is it going to retest the bottom
we don't know
we don't know and this is why you should
be taking the average but what I show
you in this example is that on this
overall sell to buy I'm going to be
showing you more examples later
um
we we take like just a simple fit and we
drop the 50 and look at where the market
came in later how did it come in I want
you to pay attention how did it come in
it tricked all the buyers it tricks all
the buyers all the buyers from here as
well massive movement to the downside
what is this it's a fake move right and
then what happens immediately afterwards
is they potentially close their
positions right there get all of their
liquidity massively pushes up well does
it create a trend change so what is the
market doing right now eat the lines
bullish what caused this trend change
you immediately track it back this is
our major higher low and within that
higher low you have that fake sale to
buy right you drove it in and this is
where the market comes in closes the
orders and continues to push up
okay so there is there is a great
example of
that supply and demand let me give you
another one
right so there you can see the patterns
right there you can see that it usually
happens around the Asian range we have a
massive range right there again what I
told you in the previous lesson what do
we have above the range and below the
range stop losses there are people in
shorts right there there are people in
Longs and on the breakout you usually
get also a lot of sellers entering and
this is what the banks want they want
the opposite order to what they actually
want to do
massive push again to see how the
accumulation happens right there it
looks like a lower high right at the
time it tries to push down launches even
new more orders and then boom what do we
have is we have a trend change very good
what happens right there stop losses of
sellers are kicking in so this is what
they want and then again what caused
this trend change right there what is
this well it looks like a base demand
Harlow right you can see the market
actually launched the fake pushed up
came into 50 then it pushed up and then
again it comes into the demand Zone
creates a new base pushes up pulls back
here we didn't really quite reach the
base then a massive push-up once again
it pulls back creates a high low high
then on the way down it creates a trend
change but you still know that you have
this base Demand right there and you can
see the market came in reacted came in
again and it's reacting
okay
so you can see the two types of supply
and demand right there in a couple of
examples we first usually have the first
example when the market is accumulating
grabbing the liquidity of everyone
creating a trend change and then you
usually find what caused the trend
change right and you enter from there
and then as the market starts making an
uptrend then this is your main task is
to actually jump on that train
okay so so far this is all Theory I
haven't really jumped into how do you
draw them and how do you do them right
let's have a look at some details so as
I keep saying those Banks or whatever
they are they will generate liquidity
patterns around those supply and demand
zones or when they plan to form a new
supply and demand Zone and again this is
done in order to gather as much
liquidity as possible and usually the
bfis will trade in the opposite
direction of the pattern they generate
by creating this cell to buy or a buy to
sell okay so do we have a double tap
what are the banks going to do is
they're going to create a buy and then
they're gonna sell why well because
people are entering at the Double top
they have their stop losses right there
and as this breaks up there are a lot of
long people that are trading the
breakout and this is exactly when they
actually launch their fake move they
move to the downside they come in they
mitigate their Freight move and launch a
new one
do you see like a bullish flag I don't
even know how a bullish flag looks like
um is this a bullish flag I don't know
right so what are you gonna do well
people are gonna be long long long long
long long long maybe they give a little
fake then they're gonna launch the fake
move stop out all the people stop loss
all the buyers get new sellers in the
market and then they're gonna initiate
and what does this create once again is
this range the fake move the market is
going to come back and then continue in
the overall direction okay so you gotta
need that little mindset shift going
forward so what are the patterns you
have to ask yourself what are the panels
that I'm seeing and what does that mean
for the majority of retail Traders what
are they gonna do what position are they
likely to enter and then respectively
what will the banks do because the banks
they will usually do the opposite
okay so there is a little bit of a Minds
chip you have to make
remember guys once again getting back to
Market structure and time frames hard
time frames will always Prevail so if
you understand the foundation of Market
structure then you are good and if you
combine Market structure with the plan
demand this is a very simple but a very
powerful system and you don't need all
of the other stuff all the the traps the
inducements the blah blah blah blah I
promise you so listen to me right now
we're gonna go and touch on
what a lot of you have been asking order
blocks right so water order blocks
what's the difference between a supply
and demand and an OB how to use them how
do you draw them we're going to get into
details so let's get into them
so what's the difference first of all
again don't listen to me I'm just a
regular guy having my knowledge having
my testing having uh read through all
the the content that is available and
actually having done the testing myself
so I have experience and I have results
to prove what I do according to me
they're almost the same right but they
have slight differences so many people
so many Traders as I mentioned in the
intro trading is unique and you have to
find your own Niche because many people
will draw supply and demand zones they
will draw order blocks in different ways
right and then there is no wrong and
there is no right way to do if somebody
comes on and tells you this is the right
way to to draw an order block sure
that's the right way for you I draw it
in a different way
right so again you have to find out what
works best for you usually
an OB according to me is the last cell
candle before the big buy or the last
buy candle before a big sell so in this
case the time frame you look at it will
matter because you can have a series of
cell candles on the 50 minute but on the
flowery chart it can just be one candle
so be aware and I'm gonna show you
examples on how exactly to draw them
what we usually try to find is the last
candle before an engulfing occurs so
this actually makes us refine a Zone
which shows us exactly where that fake
move happened where did that sell to buy
and buy to sell occurred and it looks
pretty much like this we have a bearish
candle and then you have a very nice
engulfing candle with this engulfing
candle needs to engulf the full candle
the wick and the body and then how to
usually draw them you take the candle
like this right you have a buy and then
the very big sale
that engulfs the previous candle and
again there are a lot of rules to it so
let's get into the ruse so what are the
details and the rules
we always need to see an SB after the
creation of an OB so this pretty much
forms once again our major lower higher
higher low supply and demand Zone okay
so as I told you previously why do those
major harlows work well because they
have a lot of demand inside them right
so if you remember when we have an
uptrend the market creates a trend
change and then confirms the trend
change okay this is our major High
and this is our major low
right so then usually again right here
you're gonna have
Supply and I couldn't lower high Supply
right or you can call the mobile you can
call them whatever you want this is a
strong high that caused the breakup
structure and again this is potentially
where they also launched a little bit of
fake moves so the market should not
usually go above this High Why well
because if the banks really launch the
orders right there they wouldn't like to
get a stop loss or they wouldn't like to
get further into into like a loss so
usually then you're gonna see those
highs respect perfectly because pretty
much that's where they close their uh
positions on drawdown and they enter new
ones
so always always you need the structure
break or a trend change
period always look for momentums when
when an OB is printed so if you have
like a choppy and a slow break that is
weak so don't take it once again the
candle must be fully engulfed by the
next one
okay
a lot of details so the harder the time
frame the bigger the zone and the more
important it is so I want you to
actually avoid refining too much so
don't do like a quality zone or one
hourly Zone a 50 minute Zone a one
minute Zone don't like pick one big Zone
and then refine it on all time frames
pick one time frame and use that time
frame only
also an OB is considered to be fully
mitigated or retested once it's at the
50 Mark so as I told you in the previous
example we do not know where the price
is going to stop in Reverse is it going
to be in the upper 25 this is going to
be in the middle or is it going to be a
little bit below right so if you have a
Zone like this you have 25 you have 50
and you have 75 and then what a lot of
people do is again you either enter for
the 50 or you enter from the 75 or from
the 25 or
from the open right we don't know the
price can come in and kiss it and run
away the market can come into the 25 and
run away it can come into the 15 runaway
it can come all the way to create an
equal and then run away we don't know
and as I keep telling you as everything
in the market always are also not
perfect oftentimes the price will even
not tap them or just kiss them and go
you have a Zone
the market just comes in pink and just
forgets about you you don't even get
your finger on the on the sell button
right sometimes what what could also
happen what I've seen happen is the
market can throw a little Wick and then
still reverse and that's fine right but
this is why we always wait for a lower
time frame confirmation within such a
supply and demand Zone
right so those are your rules so print
those out take note because if you lack
one of these rules your supply and
demand zone is not going to be perfect
and once again in order to keep it
really simple major structure is always
going to have supply and demand Zone
Within
so
more details
uh the zones as I told you form in many
different ways and they might confuse
you so I want you to make your drawings
systematic and draw those zones in the
same way always
so I've picked here a couple of examples
all right so you can draw this in
numerous ways there is one way to draw
it right so usually what is what you
take is the engulfed candle in this case
the engulfed candle is the bearish one
but I also like to take the highest
point because if I just take it from
here as well then I miss out on actually
what is the major high right there what
you could also do is if I just delete my
join what you could also do is you can
just take the bullish candle so you take
the whole bullish candle and all the
next candle did not engulf right there
is an engulfing here right and if we go
to a hard time frame it is going to be
engulfed okay so you can draw it like
this so in this case this is those are
the two ways that I'm gonna draw it okay
this one pause the video
enjoy it how would you draw it right
this one is rather simple
there it is so
this one it's very little so this one is
very little so use a hard time frame to
find an engulfed candle and make it
bigger what I usually do is I go to like
a hard time from like if this is the 50
minute time frame and the candle is so
small I'm gonna drop to like 20 minutes
or 25 minutes to find a bigger candle
that is engulfed because as I previously
mentioned you don't want to refine too
much and I'm going to show you why later
third example
here we have a candle that is engulfing
two candles so you pretty much have two
ways there is the first one you take
that small candle once again or you can
also take the big one and I promise you
if you go to a let's say this is the 15
minute time frame if you go on the 25
minute time frame in this case there is
going to be a perfect one candle up
massive candle down that is perfectly
engulfed okay so you also have to work
between the time frames because if you
let's say if you have a demand Zone like
this and you only keep the first one the
market can come in
and the reverse and you're like oh well
we didn't tap my zone well it didn't tap
your Zone because you're way too refined
so again have a look where the engulfing
is and see always strive to make your
zone bigger that's according to me
because else you missed on a lot of
Trades the last example how would you
draw it so again numerous ways to do so
this is how I would do it
so I would always account for the
highest tweak or the lowest Wick okay so
I'm not gonna draw it like this
just with the bullish candle because
then again you miss out on the major
High which is right there okay a lot of
you can also just draw the wick that is
perfectly fine by me right but again
it's a little bit refined so we can only
draw this week personally I like to take
the whole cell to buy and I'm gonna be
dropping to another to to a hard time
frame right there to find the best
candle and I'm gonna show you examples
in a bit okay so
study this once again have a look at all
the different ways to draw them and
again guys very important make your
drawing of the zones systematic so you
draw them exactly in exactly the same
way every single time
here is a an example
of why time frames matter and why hard
time frame is always better so once
again do not refine too much
so it's much better to keep a bigger
Zone and work your way on the lower time
frame than to refine too much and then
just not get a tap of your zone right so
essentially those supply and demand
zones or areas of value from which you
are going to be looking for entries on
the lower time frame
again a little detail so if you enter
aggressively then you would maybe want
to refine so if you're going to be
entering without a confirmation which
we're going to be covering in the next
video then of course you can refine
refine in this case what we have is a 50
minute time frame
right there and again look at this
candle this candle engulfed all of this
so in this case you can take this little
candle you can take it from here as well
or you can take the whole Zone like this
okay but what I would do is I drop to
the hourly time frame and on the hourly
time frame we have a textbook bullish
candle we have a textbook order block
right there it made a buy took liquid on
the left massively rushed lower and
caused the break of structure
and in this case I would take the hourly
Zone because it offers me a lot of
wiggle room and when the market comes in
that's when I'm going to be dropping to
the lower time frames and looking for my
energy patterns but again if you just
want to enter like in a swing trade or
you want to be refined then take your 50
minutes on set your limit right there
and stop loss above again different
strategies we're gonna touch on those a
little bit later in in the next video
pretty much
let's have a look at some examples right
I always want to give you examples we're
also later going to jump on the charts
so for me to actually show you how I do
it so this one is uh complex so you
might have to pause the video and study
right
so
we start from here and again Market
structure is key so here we have like a
bearish candle then the market pushes up
and causes a 15 minute break so we have
we have engulfing candle we have
momentum and we have a breakup structure
right and you can see the next candle
immediately comes in and retests this
area
okay so you can see like in this case as
I have said right there this bearish
candle is not engulfed by the next one
again you can make an exception you can
also take this candle which is the
engulfed one or you can go to find
another time frame where you actually
find that bearish candle being engulfed
the market pushes it creates a higher
low this according to me here is a
structure break according to my rules
there we have a train change to the
downside what caused this trend change
the last bullish candle there is the
break once again this is the supply but
I would also always account for this guy
which is our major High okay but this is
where the OB this is where the supply
happened the last Buy sell massive sell
the market comes back retests it
massively launches lower okay here
before the break what happens before the
break the market creates this bike
candle and massively launches lower okay
so then we're essentially going to be
looking for the pullback but what the
market did continue to push lower
created a lower high and launched
another massive move lower right so
again
in this case this one is too valid but I
in my strategy my very systematic system
focuses only on the most recent ones so
I'm giving a very big hint right there I
do not focus on Old supply and demand
zones
right so here in this case this is the
last bullish candle before the break the
market massively comes in right and just
breaks it so maybe we got an entry right
there I'm looking at the Wicks maybe you
got a one minute entry I'm not sure well
maybe you take a loss because again you
can see right there the market got
oversold demand kicked in and the market
is starting to reverse and there is
probably a demand Zone on the left which
is why hard time frame always matters
this is maybe a full hourly Harlow
because this is the 50 minute we're
looking at so maybe this is a higher low
the market aligns bullish right and then
have a look here
remember the old one the market comes
into the old one and actually makes a
trend change down okay uh but yeah so it
gives us like a little short-term
bearishness but again as I keep saying
keep in mind the hard time frame this is
the bearish candle it's not fully
engulfed so we have to look at a
different time frame but again look at
the engulfing candle right there that
cost uh break of structure in fact the
trend change with a lot of momentum so
this one is still relevant because it
signifies that a higher low is forming
and this is a very powerful demand Zone
because it's the one that actually
caused the trend change at a four hourly
higher low formation so very very
powerful Zone I've back tested this we
actually have it as an entry model in my
community so
what happens later is that again in
terms of the 15 minutes so again there
are a lot of details on this example in
terms of the 15 minute this is the major
high and this is the major low so we are
bearish but again according to my entry
rules I will be looking for logs from
here based on this cycle with a TC
demand Zone
the market then pulls back into the
supply that actually caused the train
change to the downside reacts reacts
reacts reacts react what is it building
right there guys let's focus what does
it build
a very big consolidation what happens
fake move below the consolidation into
the last sale to buy that was internal
so this is internal why because this is
our major high and this is our major low
anything inside is internal but you can
of course also read the internal so here
we have the sell-off and then the market
massively expanded so then again what
caused this expansion this this is the
last cell candle before the break and
yeah I sit massively pushing up so
probably it's not going to return so we
gotta right now keep following with the
with the base supply and demand that
just pushes and continues
okay so very comprehensive example study
this one there is a lot going on
um so let's explore all of these so
right now I'm gonna be so
keep all of these in mind right so I'm
gonna be dropping right now on the one
minute and actually showing you how you
can execute from those supply and demand
zones on the one minute by using the
same OB and the same supply and demand
rows so let's jump into it there is the
one that so this is the OB that calls
the TC and a potential flowery Heart
High so this should be uh this one
right so this is where we are out of 40
Heart High
right we make the first 50 minute
alignment down which means that the
pullback is starting so this is where
we're going to be looking to enter a
trade so dropping on the one minute what
do we have there is this massive range a
massive buy a massive sell-off the
market slowly pulls back pulls
blackpools back pullback tap into the
Zone give us a one minute alignment
right so then again what caused the
alignment you can see there is a little
bearish candle right there what I would
do in this case is once again I'm really
not going to look to refine too much I'm
just going to take this hole by to sell
and enter somewhere right there but I've
done this very precisely towards this
bullish candle right there you can see
the market came in very aggressively how
did it came in what a massive fake move
a massive buy stopped right there
exactly and started reversing so what is
this buy to sell right there this is the
fake move they're launching so what are
they gonna do they're gonna come back uh
take some off and then continue and
again what I usually do is I take the
buy to sell and again as I told you we
don't know if they're gonna tap the open
the 25 the 50 were the 75 in this case
they perfectly reacted from the 25
percent
of this buy to sell right so this might
be a little bit Advanced for some of you
if you're drinking this for the first
time but I know a lot of your experience
with that stuff so hopefully it makes
sense so that is the first example let's
have a look at the second Zone we have
so this is the one that uh so this is
let me show you
so this is this Zone right there the
market made a new lower low right so we
had this massive job so there is the
short trade we took this is a massive
trade if you actually of course hold it
right now we're looking to enter from
here because this is the last high this
is the last low right and we're looking
for a short however
the market comes in again what it does
here is massive sell-off pushes
consolidates pushes up so do you see any
entries here
not really if you don't enter
aggressively
are high Harlow are high Harlow yeah it
pretty much broke on this quick right
there so this Zone was immediately
invalidated and as I told you we had
like two weeks right there there are no
entries so we do not take a loss from
The Zone which is perfect okay next
example so this is the one this is the
old one
right which is a reaction point but
again even if you trade from it the
market what does the market do makes a
range it creates a massive buy it
creates a sell then comes back to retest
that buy gives us the entry okay if you
zoom in what caused the cell right well
you see here I've taken this little
bearish candle again in this time frame
you can use a different time frame to
find the proper candle you can draw it
like this you can join it like this you
can draw it in many ways what's
important is that you understand the
psychology behind it the market came in
rejected for a little bit pushed down
pulls back pushes down where does it go
into that TC
the man Zone on the left that is a
strong one Taps inside lower low lower
high lower low lower high lower low
aligns bullish there is the last cell
there is the last buy that aligned
bullish again where is the market going
to come in so if you do the mistake of
doing this in this case
you miss out on the trade so again as I
always say keep a zone bigger and if you
get a good stop loss just enter the
trade because in this case we didn't
even go to the 25 percent
right so
then we have a push up but then again if
you remember guys in this case this was
our major 50 minute high this was our
major 50 minute low so we took the long
but we also have to take the short why
well because we are also bearish the
market Taps into the zone
har High Harlow har High then it aligns
verse right there you take the trade and
we're running into profit so you can see
there are trades everywhere when you
pick the right supply and demand zones
and there is that internal uh bullish
one I just want to show you a couple of
examples we have a Nobu right there we
have a range the market pushes into it
lower low lower high lower low how does
the lower low form with a massive cell
followed by a massive buy okay so you
know ah I've seen this pattern I know
this pattern Ilya taught me this pattern
right the market comes back where does
it hold fifty percent right even here it
went to the 75 percent as well okay but
spot that I didn't do I didn't do this
what I did is the whole lick the whole
cell to buy so again I do not refine
because I've refined way too much to
enter like with a one pip stop loss it
just doesn't work I'm telling you for
now in this case it worked great so you
could have entered the trade from here
what I want to stop was and you nail a
massive Banger and that's fine if you
want to do this but the majority of the
times you're gonna be missing trades
Okay so
there are a couple of examples right and
we're going to jump on the chart so I
can actually show you how it works
another concept I actually want you to
understand is the fractal nature of the
market so what I just showed you is the
fractal nature of the market we drew 50
minute zones in the same way we do the
zones on the one minute as well okay so
the same things we repeat on every time
frame price doesn't know time and time
doesn't know price
so very important kind of a
mind-shifting sentence right there I
still kind of find it hard to really
really accept this one but it's true
right so price which is the way price
moves it doesn't know the time it
doesn't know the time frame and the time
frame doesn't know the price right
because price is price it's all the same
different time frames are just a
different representation of price right
and again as I said there are patterns
within patterns so
we can have that same thing on the
flowery the fake move the push the
retest within this flowery demand you
can have the same thing happening on the
15 minutes right there the 15 minute
gives you a range uh manipulation pushes
outside comes back to retest within
right here on the 50 minute retest you
can have the same thing on the one
minute and this is pretty much top down
analysis this is oh this is why all you
need is three time frames to be
profitable a hard time frame a middle
time frame and an ancient time frame and
all you do is apply the same pattern of
course with some more kind of additional
stuff so hopefully it makes sense there
are a couple of additional uh things
that I
teaching my program one of them I call
the rim this is kind of a real sauce
it's a very deep understanding that one
can have on supply and demand but I'm
gonna keep it away from now it's pretty
much like how actually does the the
order block form what are the different
phases within the order block and how
you can actually trade it right but
again we're not going to be covering
this in today's video another one that
that is also Worth to have a look at is
order flow so right order flow how the
market goes up how the market goes down
and how you can actually follow the
order flow and really know who is in
control but once again order flow is
spotted within Market structure
combining it with supply and demand so
right now I want to just jump on the
charts and actually find as many
examples as possible because I want you
to see me how I draw those zones how I
look into them uh what are like the
different little details that I said
like if if it's not clean on one time
frame how do you drop it on another time
frame and draw it right and we're going
to be focusing on multiple time frames
and also combining right now supply and
demand with Market structure so we're
gonna be spend some time right now on
the charts and in the next lesson I
decided in the next lesson we are gonna
touch on liquidity because for me to lay
out all the liquidity Concepts I know
it's going to take me another 40 minutes
and I don't want this video to be again
two hours so we're gonna do it in a
separate video which is going to be
easier for your Learning Journey in the
meantime if you have any questions about
the theory about what I mentioned so far
let me know in the comments okay what is
unclear is something that I explained
not making any sense am I speaking BS
right do you find hard to understand
something let me know because again
apart from those lessons later we can be
doing additional lessons with more
examples and all that stuff because my
mission is to help you prepare with all
the foundations to give you that
knowledge so you can start making
progress and then you can come to me as
a mentor so I can actually coach you uh
towards consistency towards the right
mindset the right system right because
what I give you right now is a lot of
things it's Theory right but it's a
separate thing to actually put it into a
system that is replicable right and you
can do this every single day every
single day every single day and see
consistency in your trading so let's
jump on the charts
all right so here we are on an empty EU
chart on the quality time frame I'm
completely freestyling this I don't have
anything prepared we're just gonna go on
find some supply and demand zones and on
different time frames walk you through
it how I draw them how I've set up my
chart so let's go first of all uh on my
rectangle I have uh
yeah around four to yeah six different
things I have hard times in demand hard
time frame Supply that is probably in 15
minutes okay so if you actually have a
look at my settings
um though those appear on every single
time frame because I want to see them
okay and then I have a lower time frame
demand which is yeah which is only on
the one minute right and I think five or
less what I also have is the
manipulation right so this is what I
told you about like that fake move which
we can try to spot right now and what I
also have is a range because again
usually the manipulation happens below
or above a range or of course it could
be a single high or a single low which
we're going to be speaking in the next
video okay so I actually want to start
with a trade that I just took this
morning just right now
um because it's very fresh in my mind so
what are we having right now here the
market broke structure to the upside you
immediately track it back what caused
the break of the structure it is this
one right there so I'm gonna tell you
it's this one is this a clear zone no so
the last cell candle is this guy so in
this case I can either take it like this
or what I'm gonna do in that case is I'm
gonna do five hour time frame uh the
candle is clean still not engulfed six
hourly not grade seven no eight nope so
we can see in this case uh which yeah so
there it is on the ninth on the nine
hourly time frame we have the spin bar
that is engulfed by the next one
immediately came back to retest and then
it pushed so again if you want to be
precise and if you would just don't want
to be dropping zones then you can do
this
always go upwards of the time frame you
are at don't go downwards so I'm not
gonna go to the three hourly to the two
hourly and the one hour let's refined
because then you get two refined because
then what you're gonna do is you're
gonna do this right and yeah you can see
this one worked in terms of intraday but
I'm just looking at this major zone
right now usually I'm gonna draw it like
this okay
here for example the market broke
structure to the upside okay we track it
back what is our major Harlow it's this
guy okay so what is our demand Zone well
you want to take the last cell candle
usually or you want to take the candle
that is engulfed another great example
of how the market is not perfect like in
this case
I only took this one is this engulfed
yes it has a little bit of imbalance
right there if you're looking at
imbalance it caused the break of
structure what you can also do five
hours do we have something it's pretty
much the same it's a slightly bigger
candle six hours
let's check it out
six hours it's even bigger so I'm gonna
take this right seven hours do we have
actually a bearish candle that is
engulfed not really okay so maybe nine
hourly no so in this case we just don't
have it so your task is is to make this
as bigger as possible so that you have
wiggle room and the market comes in here
to actually take a trade okay so then we
can jump in to look at what happened on
the 50 minute right there what happened
on the 50 minute right there right now
let me actually show you my trade for
today so where is the market right now
it's making a massive lower low what is
it it's uh oversold
okay what did it also do it created the
new forward break structure right there
it made a lower low and it came in and
took out the slow okay so what I'm gonna
teach you um in the next lesson is that
again old lows and highs like this they
have a lot of liquidity so when a low
like this is taken usually a pullback
initiates and this is why harlows and
her highest form when you have a high
high low high above this High there is
liquidity so when it's taken usually the
opposite side of orders are triggered so
then the market pulls back right higher
high then the market pulls back again so
when I saw this High being taken
and pretty much I didn't even see this
hat first oh the market is at a lower
low cool what are my options to either
continue flowing with the market down or
look for a counter Trend then I drop to
the 50 minute time frame all right let's
read the 50 minute what do we have right
there is our Asian range so if you
haven't watched my Asian range video
it's a good time to do so but I think
it's actually going to be even a better
time after the the liquidity lesson
right so what do we have right there is
again I'm just tracking structure we
have breaker structure right there
we have breaker structure right there
and then what happens all of a sudden is
the market creates a trend change how
did that happen let me ask you right
with this so what I do this right there
is manipulation that is our cell to buy
that cause later a train change so if
you were early in this market 7 15 you
can be looking to take a trade from here
because this is the last silk candle
that was engulfed calls the train change
pulled back and gave you a long trade
while the market does later is it makes
a breaker structure what caused the
breakup structure so again as I keep
saying the market is not perfect right
it's not perfect
this is the bearish candle right but you
can also take this one so what I will do
in this case is go to the 16 minute not
really 70 minute not really I'm here
just to tell you that uh there is no
there is no clean candle to take exactly
in this example but I know that we have
a breaker structure what is my major
Harlow it's this guy so there is demand
within this major Harlow okay so what I
did is
I dropped to the one minute
so there is that uh where's the first
trade yeah there is the first trait so
again how do you take the first trade
the market pushes up it creates this
sell-off and then it buys right and what
you can see precisely before the big buy
what do we have
is this cell where does the market go
precisely 50 of the last sale to buy
okay I do this with with the Gan tool
all right so this is the Gantt box and I
have it
like this 0 50 75 and one and almost no
background right so there we go fifty
percent boom this is actually an entry
model we have it's called the the one
minute continuation fanatic entry model
um
number three the market continues to
push up right and causes a 50 minute
break of structure what do I know is
that there is demand with me right there
so also the liquidity has been taken I'm
not going to speak about liquidity in
this lesson we had a trend change
precisely right there so then
look at this
right
same thing on the one minute that we do
same thing on the 50 minute
there is our breaker structure that I
was actually a train change what caused
this breakup structure it's this guy
okay what do we have actually right
there is we have a massive sale to buy
as manipulation what did that do range
range range range and massively went
down took everything where did it go
into the previous
sell to buy and what did it tap
50 on the spot right so there were quite
a few trays this morning but I don't
trade at six I don't trade at seven I
trade after eight so I could have taken
this but I was looking for a
confirmation because I don't trade
aggressively push pull back I took the
trade here stop loss below the major low
and uh there is my 4r trade
so lovely trade this morning right right
now actually there is a short I just
missed I just missed the short I'm
actually looking for it on my other
screen I'm looking at it on my other
screen and I was gonna take it but again
I'm doing this for you but let's break
it down let's break it down what do we
have
a little bit of a choppy market right
there but let's just follow price there
is a breaker structure right there what
caused this breaker structure according
to me it's uh this low right there it
actually could be this low but I'm gonna
take this one
what happens is we have a train change
down what is our major high is this one
where is the supply it's this one is
this a valid Supply yes it's a nice
bullish candle that is in Gold by the
next one and it calls the break of
structure right what I do is I drop on
the one minute the market comes in grabs
the liquidity what does it do takes out
the high
takes out the high what caused this high
it's this one so there's our Trend
change I should have taken this trade
because it actually broke on this candle
and you can already be in from here what
a massively tight stop loss but I was
actually looking to take it from here I
was just monitoring this chart I should
have maybe paused the video but let's
see I mean we have a live trade running
so let's see if we can get our
our four hour industry again why from
here well pretty much again what caused
this break uh it's pretty much this
whole again buy to sell right there so
this is this is where I would eventually
be looking to take a trade if I get a
good stop loss and I will be looking to
like go break even after yeah break even
and trade management separate lesson so
there is another trade uh I I did not
pause this video and take this trade
because of the time
it's uh I'm currently not not trading at
12 o'clock I stopped trading and usually
like 15 to yeah 20 to 50 minutes before
that I also look not to trade because
then the market is getting into chop
State and I'm happy with my win so I
just decided not to take this one but
let's see if it works out okay so again
textbook setup so let's go back to the
quality time frame practice a little bit
more
I wanted to break down this right there
so we have a massive push-up we have a
very nice pullback so let's actually do
this right and go and explore what is
happening within this Demand on the 15
minute okay so what is all of this so
I'm giving you a quiz right now
what is
all of this
right what is all of this right there
I hope you know this is internal
structure of the flowery range roverly
Harlow Wally har High dropping on the 50
minute let me let me break down this
internal structure it could be a good
lesson
on the 15 minute this is where we
created the trend change
what caused the trend change it is this
little guy right there which again is
not clean but this is the last buy that
caused the cell and caused the trend
change in this case what we can do is we
can do uh 25 minute
there it is 25 minute buy candle massive
cell causing the train change however I
base this on my base time frame which is
the 50 minute all I do is 4 hourly 15 1.
the only time I switch time frames is
when I want to take a nice Zone but I
pretty much know how the zone is going
to look like on the 25 when I'm on the
15. so I pretty much knew that if I go
on the 25 this is going to be a clean OB
right there what does the market do
comes back chops for a little bit and
then at the end of the day it explodes
down
exactly right there it caused the
breaker structure do we care what
happens right there no this is all
internal this is our again remember the
exercise this is our major height this
is our major low anything between these
two levels is internal of course this is
where we're going to be looking for an
entry so do you want to drop to the
laminate have a look if we got an entry
let's do so
all right so we come in oh this is very
very chopped so let's see um
boom train change what caused the train
change very clean will be in this case
there it is so what do we do is we take
our trade how do you take it are you
gonna take it from here with a one-pip
stop loss are you gonna take it to from
here for six foot stop loss I don't know
as I told you if you have this big buy
you draw your gun box and we don't know
where the market is gonna stop which is
why I always say if you get a good stop
loss just get into the trade personally
I'm gonna do it from the 25 because it
gives me a five pip stop loss and we got
our a almost 3r almost 3r
um okay so this is very debatable if we
take TP if not then I think we're
probably break even because I wouldn't
really hold the trade as it gets to 3r
and then get a stop loss so this is
either I mean if you took it from here
uh you're definitely having a take
profit on this trade right oh sorry if
you took it like this you're even having
almost a 5r again we're here not to take
trades we're here to learn the market
returns back right and actually
technically
takes out this high on the one minute
what caused this height to be taken is
this Harlow what happens is the Harlow
gets smashed the next question you ask
is okay what actually caused this Harlow
to get smashed you track it back it's
this do we have a clean Obi in this
example not really okay so how you can
draw this one is you can take this
candle because this is the candle that
was engulfed or what you can do in this
case is go two minutes
right go two minutes and there is a
slightly better candle which is still
bearish then you can do two minute no
three minutes gets a little bit bigger
okay so again experiment with it find
the time frame that works best for you
personally I'm gonna take it like this
the market comes in it came in right
there take the trade save stop loss of
three Pips and a massive Rundown
right
so you see we literally called the top
of the trend right there 40 Heart High
15 minute train change boom and again
not to say how many trades you can be
taking along the way but this again is
our entry models which we're not going
to talk about so jumping on the forage
once again what do we have is we have a
forward demand Zone the market is coming
into the following demand Zone let's see
what happens okay uh by the way I want
you to right now go in and practice all
supply and demand zones right there on
the 15 minute because they are tricky
this is where we broke right there okay
so how do you drop a demand zone right
there a supply sorry well I'm gonna take
it personally like this why because if I
go right now on the 25 minute this is
probably going to be one candle okay you
can do it like this to me this is too
refined right you can even do it like
this this is uh how uh the majority of
my community does because I've taught
them to take bigger zones and then
Master their entries on the one minute
right there so if I just quickly drop to
the 25
um not really right so 24
23 right so there is a good one right so
we have this bullish candle and I'm
always gonna take the wick so that
that's a proper Zone the market pushes
down it pulls back it pulls back to 50
but it doesn't tap our Zone well that's
fine no trade what does it go and do
later it causes a breaker structure what
caused the break of structure we'll have
a look here you have a little detail so
you have the bullish candle bearish then
this candle throws a huge Wick above and
closes so again what you can do in this
case is you can take the wick
like that you can take the wick like
this or you can take the whole candle or
go to 25 and there is your candle I mean
the 25 candle is
um it's technically engulfed by this one
maybe you do 24 minutes yeah there is so
24 minute candle bullish full engulfed
calls the braking structure what you do
the market comes in right there drops to
the one minute
uh oh yeah in this case you did not get
an entry because that's the market
aligned I remember this trade it just
made uh the the TC right there and just
forgot about us so no trade do we care
no we keep following the ranges okay so
this is actually practicing supply and
demand but I'm already marking up Market
structure as well there is a break of
structure what caused this breaker
structure track it back is this guy what
is the supply zone right there it's very
clean bullish candle
right there but always also embrace the
high
okay so don't take it like this so that
you leave out the wick right there
always embrace the high the market pulls
back doesn't get in where did it get in
inside this hole buy to sell so this is
why don't refine too much right but
don't also make it way too big so I try
to find the hap medium which in this
case if you drop to the 25 it's going to
be the 25 and it did not tap
massive push lower
there is a break of structure the market
keeps moving down what is the major high
it's this one right what is the demand
Zone again tricky right there we don't
have it perfectly okay so same example
the market creates a bullish candle then
Wicks above it and then massively drops
lower okay so what you can do is you can
do this or you can catch even the
bullish candle which is what I would do
personally catch from the buy to sell or
25 minutes
um not really
there you go 25 golden sorry 24. golden
massive drop lower that's the supply
Zone but the market did not come in okay
so right now we are in a four hourly
demand zone so what you have to be
looking for is for the 15 minute to
become bullish let's see if it actually
does there it is
Jim and it became bullish right there uh
that was a tricky price action right
here because it caused the high then it
calls the train change right there so
it's getting a little bit tricky
so I think we'll play a little bit more
yeah so there it is right so we have
this massive expansion higher then the
question you actually have to ask is
what caused this expansion higher and I
think I took a long from here because
this is what caused the expansion okay
so we have a structure break right there
uh this is also we have I have
additional rules that I'm not sharing
with you those are for my private
program because we also have the valid
ranges rules and usually a valid range
is also going to determine a valid
supply and demand Zone in this case it
was this guy so what I did is I dropped
the one minute did I take a trade here
or did I miss it
because it tapped it pushed up uh yeah
then I was looking for a one minute
intro right there and it did not
uh okay so maybe I took yes yes yes yes
yes yes so this is I took this trade by
the way
this trade like this why because again
we were bullish on the 15 minute the
market came in this is where we aligned
bullish so how again in this case how do
I drop my zone right you can do this if
you wish in this case it worked out
great because this is the actual sale
candle that was engulfed and massively
pushed up so if you want to two pip stop
looks beautiful what I do is again I
spot where is the cell
there it is right then take the gun box
if you wish in this case again perfectly
50 but while how I entered is I think I
entered a little bit it's a little bit
higher I missed some something like this
and I think that was a stop loss
oh no that's a take profit
okay I'm probably confusing the trade
but this is Friday yeah yeah so I took
the trade yeah so it looks like it's a
TP I don't even remember but there it is
simple trade bullish 15 minute one
minute online we find where it aligned
boom 3r
uh but I think yeah later yeah it
actually went quite nice this one so why
don't I remember this trade I don't know
doesn't matter right we just found it
which is pretty good what the market
does later is if I just actually remove
some drawings the market breaks
structure to the upside what caused the
break it's this is our major Harlow
again in this case the man zone is not
perfect you can take this bearish candle
but you can see this bearish candle is
not engulfed right there is a wick right
there so what you do is you go 25 is
there something
um not really
yeah on the 24 so you can see on the 24
we have this very nice bearish candle
engulfed by a bullish one I'm gonna take
this one right then you wait for the
Market to return drop to the one minute
let's see if we can take a trade right
there
um
yes so there it is
there it is so again you can see how the
market works right so again supply and
demand Concepts uh consolidates a little
bit generates the liquidity what does it
do right there
right that fake move that I told you and
there's the fake move followed usually
what I would like to see in this case is
uh momentous push up this one is very
very very choppy
what caused this uh Trend change it's
this guy is this perfect zone no right
so why I took it like this because again
I am not gonna take something like this
or something like this I'm gonna take it
bigger like that and just look to enter
with a safe stop loss the safe stop loss
in this case will be actually below the
slow which gives it a little bit bigger
so again choices you have to make
choices then in this case are you not
happy with the stop loss then wait for a
little bit lower okay but this is a
trade that I will be
personally taking and yeah so this was
the stop loss so maybe I took the win
although that is Friday yeah maybe I
took the win and then took the stop loss
probably that is the case because I
remember there was a stop loss right
there yeah yeah so I took the win and
then I took the stop loss exactly
exactly exactly so again valid trade
but the market did not move so what
happens right now is as soon as this one
is violated
we have a train change down right where
is our supply Zone well in this case
it's actually this guy because this is
the last buy which is a valid range that
actually caused the brake structure to
the downside okay so what you have to do
is wait for the market to come in but
then it immediately broke it all right
and then you just flow with the market
this is why I hate doing the flow of the
markets Tuesday because I say I'm gonna
sell from this level the market just
massively breaks above it right and then
again
what
TC right there what is the the low that
calls the TC it's this one what is the
demand Zone it's clean it's this candle
if you want to make it bigger go to a
hard time frame
right so nothing very clean so I'm gonna
keep the 50 minute you wait for the
market to tap you go on to one minute
you take your entry and um you hit TP
where is your TP at the High
okay same thing brake structure what
caused the brake structure right now we
move right there
we move right there again demand Zone
not entirely perfect but we have a
bearish candle right there that was
engulfed but remember the rule always
account for the low so you account for
the low push pull back do we tap in
oh okay yeah so this one was just
massively broken we absolutely don't get
the one minute uh entry right there Okay
so
I think this is pretty sufficient okay
so again the main rule is when you are
on the Folly time frame and you don't
have a clean zone go to the five hourly
six hourly seven hourly wherever right
when you're on the 50 minutes and you
don't have a clean Zone then go to the
25 24 whatever right so just try to pick
a proper Zone okay so if we just go and
see how our trade is looking uh like
it's chopping this is why I don't trade
at that time because it's it's shopping
around but yeah pretty much there is our
there is our kind of uh no this is wrong
there is our manipulation right the
market comes in uh well we took it from
here right but it came in again gave
again a massive reaction so we're yeah
just sitting in that trade but let's see
how it works so right now I just want to
wrap it up and have some final words
all right Fanatics I really hope you
enjoyed the lesson on supply and demand
and Order blocks hopefully it has made
sense and you are ready to actually go
in your charts and practice I really
urge you to re-watch this video at least
two more times because there was a lot
of theory and then I spent a lot of time
I hope enough time to walk you through
some charts to actually show you some
examples and even give you a hint of the
entry system that I'm going to be
teaching you after two videos in the
next video we're gonna touch on how to
understand liquidity I'm gonna break
down all the different types of
liquidity how to then add up on your
supply and demand and Market structure
knowledge you have liquidity on top then
we put it all together we add the
entries and you are absolutely ready to
crush the market so all I ask for you is
to subscribe to the channel if you like
this video make sure to turn on the
notification Bell in order not to miss
when the next video comes out and just
hit a like right and let me know in the
comments if you enjoyed it because uh I
really hope I'm providing some good
content and it really means a lot to me
when I hear it from you so wishing you
an incredible week ahead study if you
have any questions always leave a
comment or message me via email at
support
tradingfanatic.com I'm always here for
you I'm always here to help if you
needed anything or you need another idea
for videos anything at all just let me
know so right now it's study time good
luck and let me know if you have any
questions
foreign